Guide to the Arnold Carl Klebs Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Inventory, Circa 1850-1947; 29.5 linear feet (29 boxes, 1 folio)
  - Subject File III
    - Hortus Sanitatis (Box 9)
    - Appendix and List of Editions (card box) (Box 10)
    - Picture postcards (card box) (Box 10)
    - Madrid: Centro de Intercambio Intelectual Germano-Espanol (Box 10)
    - Miller (Box 10)
    - Mediaeval Academy of America (Box 10)
    - Montreal, McGill University (Box 10)
    - Mohr von Bern (Box 10)
    - Klebs, Edwin (Box 10)
    - Klebs family memorabilia (Box 10)
    - Unidentified List (Box 10)
    - Neurological Congress (Box 10)
    - New Haven, Yale University Library (Box 10)
    - New York, Misc. (Box 10)
    - Osler Club (Box 10)
    - Osler Library (Box 10)
    - Oxford Printing (Box 10)
    - Paracelsus (Box 10)
    - Paris Libraries (Box 10)
    - Pest (Box 10)
    - Pest: manuscript (Box 10)
    - Pilgrim Routes: St. James of Compostella (Box 10)
    - Rome (Box 10)
    - Schrick, Michael (*) (Box 10)
    - Schweizerische Naturforschende Gesellschaft (Box 10)
    - Type Forms (Box 10)
    - Tuberculosis (Box 10)
    - Welch, William Henry (*) (Box 10)
    - Wilmot, David (Box 10)
    - Herbal Facts and Thoughts (Box 11)
    - Vision (Box 11)
    - Surgeon-General's Office (Box 11)
    - Misc. (Box 11)
    - Notes and Clippings (Box 11)
    - Abbreviations-Medical Periodicals (Box 11)
    - Inoculation (Box 11)
    - Variolation Bibliography (Box 11)
    - Francis: Bibliotheca Osleriana (Box 11)
    - Plague ( Pest ) Tracts (Box 11)
    - Incunabula (Box 11)
    - Reviews: Lemgo (Box 11)
    - Geneve (Box 11)
    - Geneve printing (Box 11)
    - "Science" 4/6/1928 (Box 12)
    - Letter on Catheters by Benjamin Franklin (Box 12)
    - List of Names, Abriosi to Biancelli (*) (Box 12)
    - Authors from 15th to 18th Centuries (Box 12)
    - Printers (Box 12)
    - Correspondence (Box 12)
    - Chicago Tuberculosis Committee (Box 12)
    - Tuberculosis (Box 12)
    - Incunabula (Box 12)
    - Codex Sinailteus (Box 12)
    - Science-Generalities (Box 12)
    - Time (Box 12)
    - Medicine, Psychology (Box 12)
    - Space (Box 12)
    - Occult Sciences (Box 12)
    - Tissot, Simon-Andre (Box 12)
    - Celigny (Box 12)
    - Dioscorides (*) (Box 12)
    - Fatio, Nicolas de Duiller (Box 12)
    - Fracastoro (Box 12)
    - Gentile da Foligno (*) (Box 12)
    - Grossenbacher Family (Box 12)
    - Haller (Box 12)
    - Hildegarde (Saint) (Box 12)
    - "Kranker und Arzt" ("Patient and Physician") (Box 12)
    - ACK: unpublished manuscripts (Box 12)
    - ACK: "Little Writings" (Box 12)
    - ACK: "Membre a Vie", Lausanne (Box 12)
    - Reviews of ACK's Tuberculosis book (Box 12)
    - ACK: Mss. of published articles (Box 12)
    - ACK: (trans.) Bergson: "The Philosophy of Claude Bernard" (Box 12)
    - ACK: Book Reviews (Box 12)
    - Leipzig Medicine Quarterly (Box 12)
    - Archivo di Storia Della Scienza (Box 12)
    - Lausanne (Box 12)
    - ACK: "Balneology in the Middle Ages" (Box 12)
    - ACK: "The History of Infection" (Box 12)
    - ACK: "Historical Perspectives in Opthamology" (Box 12)
    - ACK: Bibliography (Box 12)
    - ACK: Photos (Box 12)
    - ACK: X-Ray of broken radius (Box 12)
    - Bonny, Sherman G. (Box 12)
    - Leonardo da Vinci (Box 12)
    - Liemgo (*) (Box 12)
    - Light, Robert U. (Box 12)
  - Correspondence
    - Welch, William H. (*) (Box 13)
    - List of Correspondents (Box 13)
    - Arloing, S & F (Box 13)
    - Avalon (Box 13)
    - Bartel, Julus (Box 13)
    - Carbonelli, G. (Box 13)
    - Billings, John S. (Box 13)
    - Biggs, Hermann M. (Box 13)
    - Cumstom, Charles G. (Box 13)
    - Darmstaedter, Ernst (Box 13)
    - Deutsche Gesellschaft... (Box 13)
    - Fischer, Dr Hermann (Box 13)
    - Probst, Charles O. (Box 13)
    - Reber, Burkhard (Box 13)
    - Simmons, George H. (Box 13)
    - Sticker, Georg (Box 13)
    - Stockman, F. J. (Box 13)
    - Strasser, Hans (Box 13)
    - Strong, Richard P. (Box 13)
    - Tricot-Royer (Box 13)
    - Ager, Louis C. (Box 13)
    - Bowditch, Dr. Vincent Y. (Box 13)
    - Chicago: TB Institute (Box 13)
    - Congress VII TB (Box 13)
    - Flick, Lawrence F. (Box 13)
    - Kelynack, T. N. (Box 13)
    - Kearing, R. E. (Box 13)
    - Kent, William (Box 13)
    - King, Herbert Maxon (Box 13)
    - Kinghorn, Hugh (Box 13)
    - Ruffer, M. A. (Box 13)
    - Ruppel, W. S. (Box 13)
    - Semon, Sir Felix (Box 13)
    - Sewall, Dr. Henry (Box 13)
    - Spahlinger, Henri (Box 13)
    - Spivak, C. D. (Box 13)
    - Thompson, Dr. W. Gilman (Box 13)
    - Trudeau, E. J. (Box 13)
    - Bibliography (Box 13)
    - Yale Medical Library (Box 13)
    - Desiderata Lists (*) (Box 13)
    - ACK Historical Collection (Box 13)
    - Misc. Corres. (Box 13)
    - Aldis, Arthur (Box 13)
    - Coquelin, C. (Box 13)
    - Bierens de Haan, J. C. J. (Box 13)
    - Daniels, C. E. (Box 13)
    - Delepine, Sheridan (Box 13)
    - Freeston, Charles Lincoln (Box 13)
    - Haberling, Wilhelm (Box 13)
    - Halla, Ludwig (Box 13)
    - Hervey, Allan M. (Box 13)
    - Johnsson, J. W. S. (Box 13)
    - Jong, R. de Josselin de (Box 13)
    - Josephson, Aksel G. S. (Box 13)
    - Krause, Allen K. (Box 13)
    - McCulloch, C.C., Jr. Col. (Box 13)
    - Marx, Alexander (Box 13)
    - Norton, Rupert (Box 13)
    - Olfele, Felix von (Box 13)
    - Paterson, Marcus (Box 13)
    - Perkins, C.E. (Box 13)
    - Pirquet, Clemens von (Box 13)
    - Ritter, Paul (Box 13)
    - Shevensteen, A.F.C. van (Box 13)
    - Woodhead, Dr. German Sims (Box 13)
    - Askanazy, Max (Box 13)
    - Brown, Laurenson (Box 13)
    - Calmette, A. (Box 13)
    - Dorveaux, Paul (Box 13)
    - Eames, W. (Box 13)
    - d'Irsay, Stephen (Box 13)
    - Klebs, Luise (Box 13)
    - Mackall, Leonard L. (Box 13)
    - Neisser (Box 13)
    - Perkins, Robert F. (Box 13)
    - Polain, M.L. (Box 13)
    - Schelling, Ernest (Box 13)
    - Smith, Sir Grafron Elliot (Box 13)
    - Voulieme, Ernest (Box 13)
    - Wilkinson, Dorothy (Box 13)
    - Schooling, Sir William (Box 13)
    - Jantsch, Heinrich (Box 13)
    - Gardy, Frederic (Box 14)
    - Garrison, F. H. (Box 14)
    - Gutenberg Museum (Box 14)
    - Malloch, Archibald (Box 14)
    - Sarton, George (Box 14)
    - Sigerist, Henry E. (Box 14)
    - Singer, Charles E. (Box 14)
    - Smith, David Eugene (Box 14)
    - Streeter, E. C. and ACK, mutual corres. (Box 14)
    - Sudhoff, Karl (*) (Box 14)
  - Writings
    - 1913-1914 History of Biology in Hospital Setting (18th C) Variolation (Box 15)
    - 1895 Ocematose (Box 15)
    - 1897 Necessity (Box 15)
    - 1900 Construction (Box 15)
    - 1903 Preliminary Report (Box 15)
    - 1903 Relative Impt. (Box 15)
    - 1903 Sanatoria (Box 15)
    - 1904 Recent (Box 15)
    - 1904 Handbook (Box 15)
    - 1905 Behring's (Box 15)
    - 1905 Report; Early Diagnosis (Box 15)
    - 1906 Chicago- Tuberculosis (Box 15)
    - 1906 Hematological Studies (Box 15)
    - 1906 Insurance (Box 15)
    - 1906 St. Moritz (Box 15)
    - Perspectives--Comprehensive Health Planning, Comprehensive Health Planning Institute, Cornell University: correspondence and conference material (Box 15)
    - 1907 Rubber Tub (Box 15)
    - 1908 Tuberculosis tests (Box 15)
    - Unpublished ms. "Anton Chekov" by ACK (Box 15)
    - 1914 History of Medicine (Box 15)
    - 1914 E. Klebs (Box 15)
    - 1916 Leonardo (Box 15)
    - 1917 Balneology (Box 15)
    - 1917 History of Infection (Box 15)
    - 1917 Palaeopathology (Box 15)
    - 1917 Tuberculosis and Military Organization (Box 15)
    - 1918 Editorial on Tuberculosis (Box 15)
    - 1925 Dispensary-Chicago (Box 15)
    - 1925 Herbal (Box 15)
    - 1918 Policy (Box 15)
    - 1925 Herbal Facts and Thoughts (Box 15)
    - 1927 Opthamology (Box 15)
    - 1929 Catalah (Box 15)
    - 1932 Syphilis (Box 15)
    - 1932 Gleanings from Incunabula (Box 15)
    - 1935 Baumgartner's (Box 15)
    - 1935 Incunable (Box 15)
    - 1936 Philosophy (Box 15)
    - 1938 Geneva (Box 15)
    - 1938 Sunbeams (Box 15)
    - 1940 Fritsche (Box 15)
    - 1940 Neuro. Cong. (Box 15)
  - Card Files
    - Pflanzenbilder auf dem Konigsberger Franzos (Plant Illustrations from the French Kingstown) (Box 15)
    - [Authors' Names and Anonymous Works] (Box 16)
    - Index of Contacts, Correspondents (Box 16)
    - Subject Index; *Galen Index (Box 16)
    - Index on plants (Box 16)
    - Clippings book-from catalogs (Box 17)
    - A-Z notes on editions (Box 17)
    - Partial index A-G (continued in Box 18) (Box 17)
    - Index H-P; P-Z (Box 18)
    - General Medical index A-Z; Books no longer in Library Author/Subject index, A-M (continued in Paige Box 20) (Box 19)
    - Author/Subject index, M-Z (Box 20)
    - Blue index A-Z (Box 21)
    - Incunabula, short title list: cross-reference Incunabula (Box 22)
    - Cross-reference of Incunabula (Box 22)
    - Geneva author index A-C (Box 23)
    - D-I (Box 23)
    - J-P (Box 23)
    - Q-Z (Box 23)
    - Index of Printers A-Z (Box 24)
    - Partial Indexes/misc. 3 x 5 (Box 24)
    - Coll. Nicolaus pol Doctor Index (Box 25)
    - Names (other than authors) Index (Box 25)
    - Author Index; Subject index (incomplete) (Box 25)
    - Partial Index, A-B (Box 25)
    - Glass negatives and printing blocks (Box 26)
    - Glass negatives and printing blocks (Box 27)
    - Glass negatives and printing blocks (Box 28)
  - Oversize
    - Memorabilia, photographs, and drawings (Box 29)
  - Oversize
    - Savonarola, Mich.; Colle, Bonus Gallus (Box 30)
    - Bartholomaeus Anglicus (Box 30)
    - Swineshead: Calculator; Valascus de Taranta: Philonium (Box 30)
    - Galen: Opera Medica (Box 30)
    - Burley, Walt: Padua, Bonus (Box 30)
    - Gentile da Foligno (Box 30)
    - Petroleon (Box 30)
    - Razi (Box 30)
    - Arbolayre-Gart: illustrations (Box 30)
  - Oversize
    General note
    Folio
    - Drawings by [Arnold Klebs] (Box 31)
- Additional Material, Accession 1987-M-063; 1; (1 box)
  Received from: Yale Medical Historical Library, 1987
  - Andreas Vesalius, 1914-1919, 1932-1933 (Box 1)
  - A.C.K. family correspondence, 1898, 1909-1943 (Box 1)
  - Edwin Klebs correspondence, 1860-1910, undated (Box 1)
  - Diaries, 1910-1936, 1941-1943 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia, ca, 1850-1938 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 1935-1936, undated (Box 1)
  - Bibliographies, undated (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1863-1938 (Box 1)
  - Manuscripts, 1925, undated (Box 1)
  - Notes, undated (Box 1)
  - Autobiographical notes, 1904, 1934, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Printed material concerning Klebs and his library including obituary notices, ca, 1943-1947 (Box 1)